hays.com.au 2018-08-25

# Privacy Policy | Hays

As part of our compliance with the Australian Privacy Principles (APP) in Australia & Information Privacy Principles (IPP) in New Zealand, Hays Specialist Recruitment (Australia) Pty Limited in Australia and New Zealand requests you read the following information regarding how we collect your personal and sensitive information (sensitive information relates to Australia only) and how we maintain, use, store and disclosure of your personal and sensitive information in connection with your possible or actual work placements and sign where indicated to acknowledge your acceptance and understanding of this information.

### We may collect personal or sensitive information about you when:

  * You complete one of our registration forms or provide any other information in connection with your application
  * We receive any reference about you
  * We receive results of inquiries that we might make of your former employers, work colleagues, professional associations or registration body
  * We receive the results of any competency or medical test or background checks including credit and criminal record checks
  * We receive any complaint or other information from or about you in the workplace
  * We receive any information about any insurance investigation, litigation, registration or professional disciplinary matter, criminal matter, inquest or inquiry in which you were involved
  * We receive any information about a workplace accident in which you are involved
  * We collect information about you from public domain sources
  * You provide us with any additional information about you  

### Your personal and sensitive information may be used in connection with:

  * Your actual or possible work placement
  * Career guidance or management
  * Your performance appraisals
  * Our assessment of your ongoing performance and prospects
  * Any test or assessment (including medical tests and assessments) that you might be required to undergo
  * Our identification of your training needs
  * Informing you of possible work opportunities or other events such as training or information sessions by direct mail/email/sms
  * Any workplace rehabilitation
  * Our management and resolution of any complaint, inquiry or investigation in which you are involved
  * Any insurance claim or proposal that requires disclosure of your personal or sensitive information
  * Undertaking criminal reference checks and other background checks, including credit checks for positions in New Zealand involving significant financial risk and otherwise as permitted by law
  * For research, development, business systems and infrastructure testing and other business purposes to assist us in providing our services to you
  * Our direct marketing to you  

### Your personal and sensitive information may be disclosed to:

  * Potential and actual employers, clients of Hays and trusted third parties who may be based outside of Australia and New Zealand
  * Hays employees and potential employers located in:
  * Australia, Belgium, Brazil, Canada, Chile, China, Czech Republic, France & Luxembourg, Germany, Switzerland & Austria, Hong Kong, Hungary, India, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Malaysia, Mexico, Netherlands, New Zealand, Poland, Portugal, Russia, Singapore, Slovakia, Spain, Sweden & Denmark, UAE, United Kingdom, USA (and any other countries where Hays may provide its services in the future) regarding possible or actual work placements and to assist us in providing our services to you
  * Referees
  * External providers of online training and induction - eg mandatory on-line OH&S Induction, and background checking agencies - eg criminal record and credit checking
  * Third party contractors/service providers for the purposes of assisting us to provide you with our services, and/or to improve the services we offer you including (a) providing us with specialised and efficient database management, development and storage and, (b) assisting with the provision of marketing communications to you. Such service providers/contractors may be based outside of Australia and New Zealand, including the USA and Canada and your information will be stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities and will only use your information for the purpose of providing services to Hays and will not use your information for any other purpose.  Where we transfer information to persons outside Australia and New Zealand we take reasonable steps to ensure that the recipients of such information do not breach the APP or IPP in relation to that information
  * Our insurers
  * A professional association or registration body that has a proper interest in the disclosure of your personal and sensitive information
  * A Workers Compensation body
  * Any person with a lawful entitlement to obtain the information

###   
If you do not give us the information we seek:

  * We may be limited in our ability to locate suitable work for you; and
  * We may be limited in our ability to place you in work

###   
Additional information contained in our privacy policy:

Our privacy policy which is located on the bottom of our website, www.hays.com.au or www.hays.net.nz contains further information about the type of information we hold and how we manage your information, including how you can, subject to some exemptions, access personal and sensitive information about you that we hold and request that it be corrected. It also sets out how you can complain about any alleged breaches of the APP or IPP and how we will deal with any complaints.

### Changes to our privacy notice:

If at any time our privacy notice or privacy policy changes, the updated details will be available on the privacy policy on our website. Any information we hold about you will be governed by the most current version of the privacy policy. 

### Contact details

Australia

The Privacy Officer  
Hays Specialist Recruitment  
Reply Paid 2135  
BRISBANE QLD 4001  
Email: [privacy@hays.com.au](mailto:privacy@hays.com.au)  
Phone: 1800 805 051 (Australia)

New Zealand

The Privacy Officer  
Hays Specialist Recruitment  
Reply Paid 2135  
BRISBANE QLD 4001  
AUSTRALIA  
Email: [privacy@hays.net.nz](mailto:privacy@hays.net.nz)  
Phone: 0800 429 769 (New Zealand) 

### Information Statement: your rights as a candidate in NSW and QLD

  * We will not charge you a fee for the purpose of finding employment including in contravention of the QLD Industrial Relations Act 1999, s408D
  * We will not engage in misleading or deceptive conduct (such as advertising a position as being available when we know no such position exists or knowingly giving misleading information to you about the nature of a position) and we will make all placements as required under applicable legislation
  * We and our employees have a working knowledge of State and Commonwealth legislation affecting the placement and employment of persons seeking work
  * If you believe that we have acted inappropriately, illegally, or in a false and misleading way you may contact the relevant department (eg Office of Fair Trading in NSW or the Department of Justice and Attorney-General in QLD, GPO Box 69, Brisbane, 4001) for information on possible action that may be taken 

FM-021-18 | © January 2018

### Your privacy is important to Hays

Your privacy is important to us. This statement outlines Hays policy on how we collect personal information and how we maintain, use, store and disclose the personal information we hold and reflects our commitment to you. It applies to all operations within Hays Specialist Recruitment (Australia) Pty Limited (“Hays”) in Australia and New Zealand, including visitors to our website.

It is the policy of Hays to respect the confidentiality of information and the privacy of individuals. Hays are bound by the Australian Privacy Principles (APP) contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (as amended) (Australian Act) in Australia; and by the Information Privacy Principles (IPP) contained in the Privacy Act 1993 in New Zealand (New Zealand Act).

The Hays privacy policy will be reviewed and updated from time to time to take account of new laws and technology, changes to our operations and practices and to make sure it remains appropriate to the changing environment. Please regularly check our privacy policy so that you are aware of these updates and changes. Any information we hold will be governed by the most current version of the Hays privacy policy.

### The Hays privacy policy is based on transparency

We are committed to being open and transparent about how we manage personal information.

### Types of personal information held by Hays and when and how it is collected

Personal information includes information regarding your contact details, work experience, qualifications, aptitude test results, opinions about your work performance (eg references), incidents at the workplace, and other information obtained or received by us in connection with your possible and actual work placements.

### Sensitive information (Australia only)

Sensitive information is a special category of personal information under the Australian Act. It is information or opinion about you, including membership of a professional or trade association or membership of a trade union; criminal record; health information, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, membership of a political association, religious beliefs or affiliations, philosophical beliefs, or sexual preferences or practices. As outlined in the Australian Act, sensitive information can, in most cases, only be disclosed with your consent.

### Collection

We may collect personal or sensitive information about you when:

  * You complete one of our application forms or provide any other information in connection with your application
  * We receive any reference about you
  * We receive results of inquiries that we might make of your former employers, work colleagues, professional associations or registration body
  * We receive the results of any competency or medical test or any background check, including credit and criminal record checks
  * We receive any complaint or other information from or about you in the workplace
  * We receive any information about any insurance investigation, litigation, registration or professional disciplinary matter, criminal matter, inquest or inquiry in which you were involved
  * We receive any information about a workplace accident in which you are involved
  * We collect information about you from public domain sources  

  * You provide us with any additional information about you

###   
Purposes and use for which we collect personal information

Your personal and sensitive information may be used in connection with:

  * Your actual or possible work placement
  * Career guidance or management
  * Your performance appraisals
  * Our assessment of your ongoing performance and prospects
  * Any test or assessment (including medical tests and assessments) that you might be required to undergo
  * Our identification of your training needs
  * Informing you of possible work opportunities, relevant candidates, or other events such as training or information sessions by direct mail/email/sms
  * Any workplace rehabilitation
  * Our management and resolution of any complaint, inquiry or investigation in which you are involved
  * Any insurance claim or proposal that requires disclosure of your personal or sensitive information
  * Undertaking criminal reference checks and other background checks, including credit checks for positions in New Zealand involving significant financial risk and otherwise as permitted by law
  * For research, development, business systems and infrastructure testing, and other business purposes to assist us in providing our services to you
  * Our direct marketing to you

###   
If you do not give us the information we seek:

  * We may be limited in our ability to locate suitable work for you
  * We may be limited in our ability to place you in work

###   
Disclosures

We may disclose your personal information (including to trusted third parties) for the purposes for which it is primarily held or for a related secondary purpose and in some cases we may only disclose information with your consent. Your personal and sensitive information may be disclosed to:

  * Potential and actual employers, clients of Hays and trusted third parties who may be based outside of Australia and New Zealand
  * Hays employees and potential employers located in Australia, Belgium, Brazil, Canada, Chile, China, Czech Republic, France & Luxembourg, Germany, Switzerland & Austria, Hong Kong, Hungary, India, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Malaysia, Mexico, Netherlands, New Zealand, Poland, Portugal, Russia, Singapore, Slovakia, Spain, Sweden & Denmark, UAE, United Kingdom, USA, (and any other countries where Hays may provide its services in the future) regarding possible work placements or to assist us in providing our services to you
  * Referees
  * External providers of on-line training and induction - eg mandatory on-line H&S Induction, and background checking agencies - eg criminal record and credit checking
  * Third party contractors for the purposes of assisting us to provide you with our services, and/or to improve the services we offer you including (a) providing us with specialised, efficient database management and development and storage and, (b) assisting with the provision of marketing communications to you. Such service providers/contractors may be based outside of Australia and New Zealand, including the USA and Canada and your information will be stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities and will only use your information for the purpose of providing services to Hays and will not use your information for any other purpose. Where we transfer information to persons outside Australia and New Zealand we take reasonable steps to ensure that the recipients of such information do not breach the APP or IPP in relation to that information
  * Our insurers
  * A professional association or registration body that has a legitimate interest in the disclosure of your personal and sensitive information
  * A Workers Compensation body
  * Any person with a lawful entitlement to obtain the information

We do not disclose information about your individual visits to the Hays’ website.

### Management of personal information

At Hays, we train our staff to respect the confidentiality of customer information and the privacy of individuals. Hays regard breaches of your privacy very seriously and any breach will result in disciplinary action being taken, dependent upon severity. Hays have appointed a Privacy Officer to ensure that our management of personal information is in accordance with this policy and the relevant Privacy Acts.

### How do we store and protect personal information?

Safeguarding the privacy of your information is important to us, whether you interact with us personally, by phone, mail, over the internet or other electronic medium. We hold personal information in a combination of secure computer storage facilities and paper-based files and other records, and take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to protect the personal information we hold from misuse, interference and loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We may need to maintain records for a significant period of time. However, when we consider information is no longer needed, we will remove any details that will identify you or we will securely destroy the records.

### How do we keep personal information accurate and up to date?

Hays takes such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that the personal information it holds and discloses is accurate, up to date, complete, relevant and not misleading. We recognise that information changes frequently with changes of address and other personal circumstances. We generally update your customer information over the telephone. Please advise your consultant when your personal details change.

If you have created a profile with Hays via our website, you are able to review and edit your personal information at any time by logging into your account and reviewing your profile. You can delete your personal information or close your account by contacting the Privacy Officer. If you do choose to close your account with Hays, Hays may retain personal information from your account as and where required by law.

### General information collected from visitors to our website

We gather information about all our website users collectively, such as what areas users visit more frequently and what services users access the most. We only use such data anonymously and in the aggregate. This information helps us determine what is most beneficial for our users, and how we can continually create a better overall website experience for you.

### Your personal information collected on the hays.com.au and hays.net.nz websites

In some instances we may need specific information about you, such as name, address, email address, telephone number etc. We will collect this information if you apply for a job or sign up for a service via our website. We may also ask you for other information such as the types of jobs you are interested in and your workplace concerns in order to provide you with the best possible service and internet experience.

### Hotjar

This website uses services provided by Hotjar Ltd. Hotjar provides services including Heatmaps, Visitor recordings, Funnels and Form Analysis, Feedback Polls, Surveys and Recruiters. The information generated by the tracking code and cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Hotjar on servers in Ireland. Through the Hotjar tracking code the information collected includes:

#### **Device-specific data**

The following information may be collected through your device and browser:

  * your device's IP address (collected and stored in an anonymized format);
  * your email address including first name and surname;
  * device screen size;
  * device type (unique device identifiers) and browser information;
  * geographic location (country only);
  * preferred language used to display the webpage.  

####  **Log data**

Our servers automatically record information which is created upon using Hotjar. Data includes:

  * referring domain;
  * pages visited;
  * geographic location (country only);
  * preferred language used to display the webpage;
  * date and time when website pages were accessed;

Hotjar will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Hotjar uses a variety of services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics and Optimizely. These services may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, such as cookies or your IP request. For information on how Google Analytics and Optimizely collect and use your information, please refer to their privacy policies. By continuing to use this website, you consent to the processing of the above data by Hotjar and by the third parties used by Hotjar in accordance with their respective privacy policies. The cookies used by Hotjar have differing durations; some are 365 days, some persist for the session only.

To opt out please go to the following link:

<https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>

### Enquiries & complaints

You can make enquiries, requests to access/delete or correct your information, or complain about alleged breaches of the APP’s or IPP’s to our Privacy Officer: 

**Australia  **  
Privacy Officer   
Hays   
1800 805 051   
02 9236 4110   
Reply Paid   
GPO Box 2135  
BRISBANE QLD 4001

**New Zealand**  
Privacy Officer  
Hays  
0800 429 769  
\+ 61 2 9236 4110  
GPO Box 2135  
BRISBANE QLD 4001   
AUSTRALIA 

### Complaints

We aim to acknowledge receipt of all complaints within 10 working days, and aim to resolve all complaints within 30 working days. This may not be possible in all circumstances depending on the contents of the complaint. In this situation, we will respond to your complaint in a reasonable time. If you are not satisfied with our response to your complaint, in Australia you can contact the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC); or in New Zealand you can contact the Office of the Privacy Commissioner.

### Access

Subject to some exceptions that are set out in both the Australian Privacy Principles and the New Zealand Information Privacy Principles you can gain access to the personal information that we hold about you.

To make a request to access your personal information, you will need to complete an application form verifying your identity and specifying what information you require. Please contact our Privacy Officer for an application form. We will respond to your request within a reasonable period after the request is made and provide access to the information in the manner requested, if it is reasonable and practicable to do so.

We may impose a moderate charge in providing access. Our Privacy Officer will discuss this with you. You should also anticipate that it may take time to process your application for access as there may be a need to retrieve information from storage and review it in order to determine what information is relevant.

If we refuse to provide you with access to your personal information, we will notify you in writing of the reasons for the refusal and the process for escalation regarding this refusal.

### Correction

You may request that we correct the personal information that we hold about you if you deem it to be inaccurate, incomplete, out-of-date, irrelevant or misleading. We will take reasonable steps under the circumstances to correct the information.

If we refuse to correct your personal information, we will notify you in writing of the reasons detailing our refusal to correct the information and the process for escalation regarding this refusal. Should we refuse you may ask us to place with the information a statement that the information is inaccurate, incomplete, out-of-date, irrelevant or misleading and we will take such reasonable steps under the circumstances to associate the statement with your information. If you wish to exercise your rights of correction you should contact our Privacy Officer for an application form. We will not charge you for making the request to correct your information, correcting the information, or associating a statement.

### Feedback

Hays have several areas on our website where you can submit feedback, under the ‘contact us’ section. Any feedback that is submitted through this area becomes the property of Hays. We may use this feedback, such as success stories or responses to surveys, for marketing purposes, or to contact you for further feedback on the site.

HP-020-18 | © January 2018

**  
COOKIES & PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy (together with our [Terms of Use](https://www.hays.co.uk/general-content/terms-and-conditions-2989) and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which all personal data that we collect from you, or that you provide to us via the Hays.co.uk website and any other Hays group websites, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

Skip straight to the section on [cookies](https://www.hays.co.uk/PrivacyPolicy/index.htm#cookies).  
Updated: 14 Mar 2017

If you're looking for information about how to have your details removed from Hays.co.uk, [please refer to our FAQs](https://www.hays.co.uk/features/site-help-1417603).

### What if I do not agree with this Privacy Policy?

If you do not agree to our processing of your data in the manner outlined in the Policy, please do not submit any personal data to us. 

### Who is the controller of the data that you provide to us?

Hays Specialist Recruitment Limited is registered as a data controller in the United Kingdom for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998. We ensure that the data you supply to us is processed fairly and lawfully, and with skill and care and used only for the purposes set out in this policy.

### What information will we collect? How will we use it?

We will collect data about you, both personal data (such as your name and contact details) and also sensitive personal data (such as information in your CV). The personal data and sensitive personal data will be stored, processed, used and disclosed by us in the following ways:

  * To provide our recruitment services to you and to facilitate the recruitment process
  * To assess data about you against vacancies which we judge may be suitable for you
  * To send your information to clients in order to apply for jobs or to assess your eligibility for jobs
  * To enable you to submit your CV, apply online for jobs or to subscribe to alerts about jobs we think may be of interest to you
  * To allow you to participate in specialist online training services
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service when you choose to do so
  * To market our, full range of recruitment services to you (permanent, temporary, contract, outplacement and recruitment process outsourcing services)
  * To enable us to develop and market other products and services and where you have consented to being contacted for such purposes
  * To improve our customer service and to make our services more valuable to you (including tailoring our website and our group companies websites when you log on to enrich your personal online experience)
  * To send you details of reports, promotions, offers, networking and client events and general information about the industry sectors which we think might be of interest to you where you have consented to being contacted for such purposes
  * To answer your questions and enquiries
  * To third parties where we have retained them to provide services that we, you or our client have requested including references, qualifications and criminal reference checking services, verification of the details you have provided from third party source, psychometric evaluation or skill test
  * To third parties, regulatory or law enforcement agencies if we believe in good faith that we are required by law to disclose it in connection with the detection of crime, the collection of taxes or duties, in order to comply with any applicable law or order of a court of competent jurisdiction, or in connection with legal proceedings
  * To use your information on an anonymised basis to monitor compliance with our equal opportunities policy
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us

From time to time we may seek your consent to process, use or disclose your information for any other purpose not listed above.

We may also pass your information to, or allows access to such information to the Hays group of companies, whose locations can be found at www.hays.com in order that they may use your personal information in the same way as we process, use and disclose your information as described above.

We reserve the right to transfer your information to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of this Privacy Policy and provided that the third party only uses your Personal Data for the purposes that you provided it to us. You will be notified in the event of any such transfer and you will be afforded an opportunity to opt-out.

### Where will my information be held? Where will it be accessible from?

The personal information that you provide to us (including sensitive personal information) may be accessible by other Hays group companies, clients, and the third parties specified above. Some of these Hays companies, clients and third parties are located outside of the European Economic Area. Accordingly your personal information will be sent to or be capable of being accessed from outside the European Economic Area. When we transfer your personal information outside the European Economic Area we will take steps with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

### How do I find out what information you hold? Can I amend, modify or require my information to be deleted? Can I unsubscribe to your services?

You may request us to confirm what information we hold about you at any time and may request us to modify, update or delete such information. We may ask you to verify your identity and for more information about your request. We also have the right to charge an administrative fee for this service. Where we are legally permitted to do so, we may refuse your request and will give you reasons for doing so. We will seek to act on your request in the timescale required by applicable data protection laws.

You may request to unsubscribe from job alerts and marketing material at any time. If you wish to contact us with respect to the above matters please email us at [customerservice@hays.com](mailto:customerservice@hays.com).

### How long will you hold my information for?

We are required by law to hold your information for as long as is necessary to comply with our statutory and contractual obligations and in accordance with our legitimate interests as a data controller.

We will use reasonable endeavours to ensure that your Personal Data is maintained and up to date. However, you are under a duty to inform us of any and all changes to your Personal Data to ensure that it is up to date and we will update or delete your Personal Data accordingly.

### Sending us information over the internet

Your information is held on servers hosted by us or our Internet Services Provider. The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

### How we collect and aggregate information about visitors to our websites

We also collect information about the way job seekers and visitors use this website in order to improve our services. We do not use information gained in this manner in a way that any individual can be identified, and will use it to understand our users better, and to determine aggregate trends, most popular pages, etc, for all the website’s users. We may share this kind of aggregate data with selected third parties to assist with these purposes where you have consented to this. We may also undertake marketing profiling to help us identify services or jobs which may be of interest to you.

### Cookies

**1\. What are cookies?  
**A ‘cookie ‘ is a piece of information that is stored on your computer's hard drive and which records your navigation of a website so that, when you revisit that website, it can present tailored options to you based upon the stored information about your last visit. You can normally alter the settings of your browser to prevent acceptance of cookies.

Cookies are used by nearly all websites and do not harm your system.

**2\. How do we use cookies?  
**We use ‘cookies’ to:  
1\. monitor site user traffic patterns and site usage. This helps us to understand how our users use our websites so that we can develop and improve the design, layout and functionality of the sites; and   
2\. to help us to advertise to you jobs we think you will be interested in

There are different kinds of cookies with different functions:

Session cookies: these are only stored on your computer during your web session. They are automatically deleted when the browser is closed. They usually store an anonymous session ID allowing you to browse a website without having to log in to each page. They do not collect any information from your computer.

Persistent cookies: a persistent cookie is one stored as a file on your computer, and it remains there when you close your web browser. The cookie can be read by the website that created it when you visit that website again. We use persistent cookies for Google Analytics (see section 6on Google Analytics) and for personalisation cookies (see section 7 on Personalisation Cookies).

The only third party cookies we use on our site are Google Analytics (please see section6 on Google Analytics)

The cookies we use are explained below:

**3\. Strictly necessary cookies  
**These cookies are essential to enable you to use the site effectively such as applying for a job and therefore cannot be turned off. Without these cookies, the services available to you on our site cannot be provided. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you have been on the internet.

**4\. Performance cookies**  
These cookies enable us to monitor and improve the performance of our site. For example they allow us to count visits, identify traffic sources and see which parts of the site are most popular. We use Google analytics for this purpose (see section 6) and all information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore remains anonymous. These cookies do not collect information that identifies a visitor, as all information these cookies collect is anonymous and is only used to improve how our site works.

**5\. Functionality cookies**  
These cookies allow our website to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you are in) and provide enhanced features. For instance, a website may be able to provide you with news or updates relevant to the policies you buy. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, font and other parts of web pages that you can customise. They may also be used to provide services you have requested such as viewing a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect is usually anonymised.

**6\. Google Analytics**  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (‘Google ‘). Google Analytics uses cookies to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Google uses the __utma cookie. This is a persistent cookie that expires in two years. With each new visit, the expiration date is refreshed. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

**7\. Personalisation cookies**  
This website uses personalisation cookies which help us to advertise to you jobs that we think may be of interest. These cookies are persistent (see section 2 above) and mean that when you log in or return to the website you may see advertising for jobs that are similar to jobs that you have previously browsed.

For information on how to reject these personalisation cookies, see section 8 below.

**8\. How to reject cookies**  
If you don’t wish to receive cookies that are not strictly necessary to perform basic features of our site you may choose to opt out of them by selecting the appropriate box on the top right hand side of this page.

Note that most web browsers will accept cookies, but if you would rather that we did not collect data in this way you can choose to accept all or some or reject cookies in your browser's privacy settings. Rejecting all cookies means that certain features cannot then be provided to you and accordingly you may not be able to take full advantage of all our website's features. Each browser is different, so check the ‘Help’ menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

For more information generally on cookies, including how to disable them, please refer to aboutcookies.org (<http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>). You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your computer.

**9\. Hotjar**  
This website uses services provided by Hotjar Ltd. Hotjar provides services including Heatmaps, Visitor recordings, Funnels and Form Analysis, Feedback Polls, Surveys and Recruiters. The information generated by the tracking code and cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Hotjar on servers in Ireland. Through the Hotjar tracking code the information collected includes:

  * Device-specific data 

The following information may be collected through your device and browser:

  * our device's IP address (collected and stored in an anonymized format)
  * your email address including first name and surname
  * device screen size
  * device type (unique device identifiers) and browser information
  * geographic location (country only)
  * preferred language used to display the webpage
  * Log data

Our servers automatically record information which is created upon using Hotjar. Data includes:

  * referring domain
  * pages visited
  * geographic location (country only)
  * preferred language used to display the webpage
  * date and time when website pages were accessed  

Hotjar will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Hotjar uses a variety of services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics and Optimizely. These services may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, such as cookies or your IP request. For information on how Google Analytics and Optimizely collect and use your information, please refer to their privacy policies. By continuing to use this website, you consent to the processing of the above data by Hotjar and by the third parties used by Hotjar in accordance with their respective privacy policies. The cookies used by Hotjar have differing durations; some are 365 days, some persist for the session only.

To opt out please go to the following link: <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>

**10\. Adroll**  
This website uses services provided by AdRoll. AdRoll provides services including Prospecting, Retargeting, Cross Device, SendRoll and Online Behavioral Advertising by using cookies. The information generated will be transmitted to and stored in Amazon’s cloud (A3) in their data centers in the US and other countries. Data may be collected for targeted advertising and data collected may be used to target advertising on other sites or applications based on your online activity.

The types of data collected include:

  * Pages visited
  * Date and time of visit
  * Location using IP address
  * Hashed Email Addresses  

You can opt out of receiving targeted advertising from Adroll by visiting [http://youronlinechoices.eu](http://youronlinechoices.eu/)

### Links to other websites

Please note that clicking on links and banner advertisements and RSS feeds may result in your transfer to another website, where data privacy practices may be different to this Privacy Policy. It is your responsibility to check other website privacy policies to ensure that you are happy for your personal information to be used in accordance with those third parties privacy policies. We accept no responsibility for and have no control over third party websites, links, adverts or RSS feeds or information that is submitted or collected by third parties.

### Change to our Privacy Policy

Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this website so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any time we decide to use Personal Data in a manner significantly different from that stated in this Privacy Policy, or otherwise disclosed to you at the time it was collected, we will notify you by email, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in the new manner.
